Madhavi Giduthuri

+91 80744 70381, madhavi.giduthuri@gmail.com

Objective:

A professional developer with nearly 2 years of experience in building, developing and maintaining user-facing web applications to enhance user experience and functionality. Seeking a challenging position in a fast-paced environment where I can learn, use and enhance my skills and experience to make a significant contribution towards organizational goals by ensuring professional and personal growth.

Experience:

MERN Full Stack Apprenticeship 06/2022 – 05/2023

NxtWave Disruptive Solutions, Hyderabad, India

- Trained at CCBP 4.0 Intensive Program designed to build skills in developing web applications endto-end
- Learned to use HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS.
- Developed a strong understanding of the full web development lifecycle.
- Completed projects and assignments under the guidance of experienced mentors.

Associate Software Engineer 06/2021 – 02/2022

Great Four Systems Private Ltd, Hyderabad, India

- Experience with Source Code Control Systems such as Tortoise SVN.
- Experience with Data Accessing using Data Adapter, Reader and Dataset for data manipulation.
- Proficient in developing systems using Tables, Triggers, Views and Stored Procedures and managing the database, data conversion, loading and implementing the systems.
- Work closely with the business, quality and support team to develop applications.
- Completed assigned tasks and reached targets within the stipulated time.
- Created technical documentation, sharing knowledge, ideas and solutions with the development team.
- Support the team on technical issues.

Technical skills:

Front-End: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, Redux

Back-End: Express, NodeJS

Databases: SQLServer2008/2014/2016/2017, SQLite, T-SQL

Methodology: Agile

Tools: VS Code, JIRA, GIT, SVN, Bugzilla.

Technical Projects:

Reddy's Laboratories IDMP, Health – Canada Integrations (Europe, Canada)

Role - Database Analyst

Versions - Harmony4.1, SQL Server 2017, MVC, .Net, SPOR, FDA Integration.

The Scope of the project is developing as back end and front-end application to discontinue the Manual process, and switching over from time consuming MS Access, multiple excel sheets and Ready Tool based XEVMPD- submission, Master data process to a fully integrated electronic process that provides easy to use interfaces with data security to the user, manage the complete Regulatory Affairs submission data flow process of maintaining and reporting Regulatory information more accurately.

Responsibilities:

- Design, develop complex solutions using MVC, SQL Server 2017, complex logics in procedures.
- Worked on encrypting the browser sessions to secure the application.
- Used AJAX Controls to create an interactive Web Application and customize AJAX Control Toolkit as per requirement demand.
- Working on Table Functions and Stored Procedures as per the business requirement.
- Worked on Active Directory integration, SSL Certificate, Secure applications.
- Responsible to generate the licenses, support, review RCA forms.

Encube Ethicals Pvt. Ltd.

Role - Database Analyst

Versions - Harmony4.1, .Net, MVC, SQL Server 2014.

The Scope of the project is developing as Back-end and Front-end application to discontinue the Manual process, and switching over from time consuming MS Access, multiple excel sheets and Ready Tool based XEVMPD- submission, Master data process to a fully integrated electronic process that provides easy to use interfaces with data security to the user, manage the complete Regulatory Affairs submission data flow process of maintaining and reporting Regulatory information more accurately.

Responsibilities:

- Design, develop complex solutions using MVC, SQL Server 2017, complex logics in procedures.
- Worked on encrypting the browser sessions to secure the application.
- Design, develop, model and modify, prepare technical design documents, perform code reviews, debugging and testing.
- Work on SSMS and Visual studio integration to design and develop schemas, tables, attribute views, analytical views, calculations views, procedures and table functions.
- Used AJAX Controls to create an interactive Web Application and customize AJAX Control Toolkit as per requirement demand.

Self Projects:

Technologies Used: React JS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REST APIs

Jobby App Web Application

Implemented Jobby App where users can log in and can see a list of jobs with search by Job title, filters based on Salary range and Employment type, etc.

Link: https://jobbyappgmadhu.ccbp.tech/

IPL Dashboard Web Application

Each Job item is fetched dynamically using REST APIs and data is shown only after logging into the web app. And also created the job details page.

Link: https://ipldashboardgm.ccbp.tech/

Money Manager Web Application

Users are able to add incomes and expenses and also can able to see all the transaction history and also know about the balances and totals.

Link: https://moneymanagergm.ccbp.tech/

Educational Qualifications:

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

Raghu Institute of Technology, Visakhapatnam 2013 - 2017